A Doll's House is a drama film directed by Joseph Losey.
Nora Helmer lives a quiet life with her husband,
Torvald, in a small Norwegian town.
While he works diligently at a bank, she looks after their children.
But Torvald doesn't know that several years ago, when he was very ill and she was desperate for money,
Nora forged a loan document and has been secretly working to pay the money back ever since.
The arrival of her friend Kristine prompts Nora to
re-evaluate her life and confront Torvald.
Nora Helmer, played by Jane Fonda.
Nils Krogstad, played by Edward Fox.
Dr. Rank, played by Trevor Howard.
Kristine Linde, played by Delphine Seyrig.
Torvald Helmer, played by David Warner.
Olssen, played by Pierre Oudrey.
A Doll's House is a 1973 drama film directed by Joseph Losey, based
on the 1879 play A Doll's House by Henrik Ibsen.
It stars Jane Fonda in the role of Nora Helmer and David
Warner as her domineering husband, Torvald.
Losey's version of the play was extensively adapted for film.
From Ibsen's expository dialogue, entire new scenes were developed by British
dramatist David Mercer and integrated through a number of invented sets.
The film explores themes of friendship, feminism, based on
play or musical, friends, women's rights.
The tone is emotional.